Jonathan Carey

Jonathan.carey13@yahoo.com 812.821.6304

Bloomington, IN

https://jonathancarey13.github.io/Portfolio2.0/https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-carey-ab5467a2/

Objective:

Multimedia professional with 3 years professional experience and a Software Developer. Focus on facilitating the growth of clients' businesses via multimedia production and design. One of my personal goals is to design, develop and deploy a video game for consumer use.

Education:

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, January 2020
 - 24-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, realworld project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training
- Indiana University, Bachelor of Arts, Bloomington, Indiana, May 2017
 - Build the skills to create film, television, digital, screen and aural media
 - Explore the critical, cultural, historical and aesthetic sides of film, television and other media forms.

Competencies & Functional Skills:

Problem solving, troubleshooting, creativity, visual communication, customer service, critical observation and thinking, organization, Agile methodology, portfolio development, addressing and resolving business challenges

Technical Skills:

Languages: C#, ASP.NET, API development, HTTP methods, MVC, pair programming

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum
Testing Tools: Unit Testing

Databases: SQL Server, relational databases

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, stateless components, session validation, responsive web design

Technical Projects:

- Text Adventure Game https://github.com/JonathanCarey13/TextGame
 - Utilized C# to create a text based adventure game
- Menu Applications https://github.com/JonathanCarey13/GoldBadgeChallenges
 - Utilized C# to create different menu applications for storing data.
- A Home Inventory API https://github.com/weswolff/BBNEighT/tree/main
 - Collaboratively utilized JavaScript and C# to create a program that can store household items for documentation incase of theft or damage
- Video Game Management Web App https://github.com/JonathanCarey13/Underwatch
 - An N-Tier architecture MVC Web Application that allows users to catalogue games and news updates for their games.

Professional Experience:

Film Freelancer , Indianapolis, IN, August 2017 – May 2020

- Collaborating with creative teams and departments to achieve a client's anticipated vision
- Building, maintaining, and deconstructing custom scene structures used for film productions
- High Competence in problem solving and expert judgment for conflicts

Film Archvist, Bloomington, IN, October 2019 - Present

- Collaborating with clients to repair, clean and digitalize physical film
- Recognizing a film's specific requirements to perform color grading and color corrections during digitalization

Facility Operations and Services, Bloomington, IN, August 2013-August 2016

- Facilitating departmental moves, installations and general assistance
- Priority delivery of time sensitive documents